José Romero

Washington, DC | 443-848-0869 | jdromerov88@gmail.com | jr@josedromero.com https://josedromero.com | https://linkedin.com/in/josedromero | https://github.com/jdromero88

Full-Stack Software Developer

Full-Stack developer with a passion for agile development of all kinds with experience in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React JS, Redux and a background in Computer Engineering. Strong teamwork skills, having worked at entry level to management. I have vast experience building teams and creating an environment that encourages extraordinary results. Dependable and always willing to take on any task and learn something new.

> Skills Languages

JavaScript, React JS, Redux, NodeJS, Ruby, Rails, SQL, HTML, CSS, Git, JSON, PostgreSQL, Linux, Wordpress.

English, Spanish, Guarani, Portuguese (basic).

Technical Projects

Flati//Life - GitHub Backend | GitHub Frontend

Social Network for Flatiron Students that aims to help new students survive bootcamp by curating a collection of fellow students projects and experiences. (SPA)

- Developed a Rails API backend with endpoints for users, projects, cohorts, technologies.
- + Utilized BCrypt gem to stored encrypted user information.(server-side)
- Built User Interface with React JS and managed states with Redux.
- Utilized Semantic UI React framework with custom CSS.

Sports Buddy - GitHub

Single Page Application that helps users connect with people in their area to play sports.

- Developed a Rails API backend using strong params, validations and endpoints for games, users, users games.
- Utilized postgresql for the database and gem BCrypt to encrypt the user information.
- + Utilized vanilla javascript with Semantic UI framework with custom CSS to build the User interface.

Vapor - GitHub Backend | Github Frontend

App that allows users to create a collection of games that they want to buy or already own. (SPA)

- Constructed a Rails API backend with endpoints for users, games, owned_games.
- Utilized postgresql for the database and gem BCrypt to encrypt the user information.
- + Utilized RAWG Video Games Database API to pull and parse data of the games.
- Built User Interface with React JS with Semantic UI React.

Experience

Apprentice Manager, **Chipotle**, Washington DC, DC

05/2016 - 05/2019

- Selected outstanding crew members and managers, train every employee effectively.
- Supervised service managers and kitchen managers, building a rapport with them to ensure their duties were performed in accordance with Chipotle standards.
- Managed employee schedule and achieve annual sales and cash flow plan.

Computer Technician, Ministry of Agriculture and Livestock, San Ignacio, Paraguay

11/2009 - 06/2015

- Provided IT support for the Department of Agriculture in the San Ignacio office: which involved installing PC software, problem solving hardware and internet connectivity issues, and acting as helpdesk support.
- Offered staff training on Microsoft Office Suite.
- Maintained all computers and equipment: managing inventory processes

Education

Flatiron School 10/2019 - 02/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program Universidad Catolica, San Ignacio Paraguay

2007 - 2012

Completed coursework in Computer Engineering; graduation pending thesis.